Register of the Constantine L. Zakhartchenko papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
  - Subject file, 1924-1985 and undated.
    - Association of Russian Imperial Naval Officers in America, Inc., 1953-1982, undated
      - Minutes of meetings, statutes, 1953-1972 (Folder 13: 6)
    - Dissidents--USSR, 1972-1978 (Folder 13: 7)
      Clippings
    - Education—Soviet Union, 1957-1963, undated (Folder 13: 8)
    - Goleniewski affair, 1966 (Folder 13: 9)
    - Kamkin bookstore, 1974-1982, undated (Folder 13: 10)
      Catalog, clippings, invoices
    - Kommunisticheskaia partiia sovetskogo soiuza, 1969-1978 (Folder 13: 11)
    - Mishtowt, Illarion Vikent'evich and Irina, undated (Folder 13: 12)
      clippings
    - Museum of the Russian Imperial Navy, 1967-1979, undated (Folder 13: 13)
      Also known as Naval Museum, Russian Naval History Museum. Clipping, contract, correspondence, maps, notes, two prints
    - Office of Naval Research, 1958-1979 (Folder 13: 14)
      Clippings, correspondence, memos, reports
    - Romanov, House of
      - General, 1965, undated (Folder 13: 15)
      - Tsarevich Aleksei Nikolaevich, 1958-1962, undated (Folder 13: 16)
        Correspondence, notes, receipts, relating to portrait of. Includes one negative and ten prints
    - Russia--History
      - General, 1970-1985, undated (Folder 13: 17)
      - Lectures, undated (Folder 13: 18)
    - Russians--Foreign countries--Germany, 1961-1963, undated (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Sheremet'ev, Sergei V., 1943, 1968 (Folder 14: 2)
    - Smyrnow, Wassily, 1969-1975 (Folder 14: 3)
      Includes articles, clippings, notes, patent
    - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr Isaevich, 1973-1980 (Folder 14: 4)
    - Soviet science and technology, 1958-1980, undated (Folder 14: 5)
      Clippings, notes, and report
    - Soviet Union
      - Aeronautical engineering, 1979 (Folder 14: 6)
      - Armed forces, 1976-1981, undated (Folder 14: 7)
      - Defenses, 1977-1985 (Folder 14: 8)
        Article, clippings
      - Economic conditions, 1971-1972 (Folder 14: 9)
      - Foreign relations--China, 1958-1976, undated (Folder 14: 10)
      - History. General, 1947-1985, undated (Folder 14: 11)
      - History--Revolution, 1917-1921 (Box-folder 15: 1)
      - Intellectual life, 1969-1984 (Folder 15: 2)
    - Space race--Soviet Union--History, 1959-1978, undated (Folder 15: 3)
    - Spies--Soviet Union, 1971-1972, undated (Folder 15: 4)
    - Stalin, Joseph, 1973, undated (Folder 15: 5)
    - Still, Joseph W., 1957-1985, undated (Folder 15: 6)
      Articles, clippings, correspondence, notes
    - Submarine technology, 1980-1984, undated (Folder 15: 7)
      Clipping, correspondence
    - Toutorsky, Basil P., 1984, undated (Folder 15: 8)
      Biographical information, sheet music
    - Tower, Jeremiah, 1973-1985, undated (Folder 15: 9)
    - Zimmerer, Mary Jane Bell, 1953 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Photographs, 1915-1985, undated
    Three hundred seventy two prints, eighteen negatives, eighteen copies
    - 1915-1984 (Folder 16: 2)
      Photographs of family, and graduates of "Morskoe uchlishche," fifty-seven prints, ten negatives, five photocopies
    - Association of Russian imperial naval officers in America, Inc. Biulleten', 1977-1979 (Folder 16: 3)
      Twenty-three prints, four negatives, six photocopies
    - Chan, Wing Kon, 1941-1984 (Folder 16: 4)
      Fifteen prints
    - Family and friends, 1912-1956, undated (Folder 16: 5)
      Thirty-nine prints
    - Friends, 1968-1984, undated (Folder 16: 6)
      Nine prints
    - Kibort, Leonid, 1945-1983, undated (Folder 16: 7)
      Twenty prints
    - Louie, Harry, 1982 (Folder 16: 8)
      Six prints of family members, including wedding photos
    - Malta, visit to, 1985, undated (Folder 16: 9)
      Eighteen prints
    - McDonnell aircraft corporation
      - Undated (Folder 16: 10)
        Four prints
      - Photo album, Sixty-six prints, and clippings relating to Zakhartchenko's projects, undated (Folder 16: 11)
    - Morskoe uchilishche, 1915-1984, undated (Box-folder 17: 1)
      Twenty prints, three negatives
    - Morskoi korpus
      - 282 Anniversary, 1983 (Folder 17: 2)
        Ten prints
      - 1916-1961, undated (Folder 17: 3)
        Twelve prints, one negative
      - 1916-1978, undated (Folder 17: 4)
        Nineteen prints, two photocopies
      - 1916-1982, undated (Folder 17: 5)
        Sixteen prints, three photocopies
      - 1917-1983, undated (Folder 17: 6)
        Twenty-two prints, two photocopies
    - Russkii morskoi muzei, 1968 (Folder 17: 7)
    - Shimanovskii, Iurii Olegovich, undated (Folder 17: 8)
    - Staub, Nancy L., 1984, undated (Folder 17: 9)
      See also Correspondence/Staub, Nancy L.
    - Tsarevich Aleksei Nikolaevich, undated (Folder 17: 10)
      One print, taken of original oil portrait
    - Zakhartchenko, Constantine, undated (Folder 17: 11)
      Eleven prints, including caricature
- Printed matter, undated. (Box 18-38)
  Clippings from various émigré newspapers and some U.S. and Soviet press relating to general topics as well as aeronautics, the Imperial Russian Navy, and Russian history and culture. Not filmed. Originals retained by Holy Trinity Seminary